<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Tour Guide</string>
    <string name="East">Eastern Alexandria</string>
    <string name="West">Western Alexandria</string>
    <string name="middle">Middle Alexandria</string>
    <string name="songs">Songs</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="stanly">It is the first bridge in Egypt to be constructed into the sea , with total length of 400 m. Considered of 6 spans , It constitute amajor part of the reconstruction and decoration of Alexandria cornich . A master piece of architectureal precision, the bridge preserves the architectural style of the famous and cosmopolitan Egyptian city.</string>
    <string name="pompey">Pompey Pillar  is a Roman triumphal column in Alexandria, Egypt,the largest of its type constructed outside the imperial capitals of Rome and Constantinople, located at the Serapeum of AlexandriaThe only known free-standing column in Roman Egypt which was not composed of drums,it is one of the largest ancient monoliths and one of the largest monolithic columns ever erected</string>
    <string name="heracleion">Heracleion , also known by its Egyptian name Thonis and sometimes called Thonis-Heracleion, was an ancient Egyptian city located near the Canopic Mouth of the Nile, about 32 km (20 miles) northeast of Alexandria. Its ruins are located in Abu Qir Bay, currently 2.5 km off the coast, under 10 m (30 ft) of water. A stele found on the site indicates that it was one single city known by both its Egyptian and Greek names.[3] Its legendary beginnings go back to as early as the 12th century BC, and it is mentioned by ancient Greek historians. Its importance grew particularly during the waning days of the Pharaohs</string>
    <string name="montaza">The extensive Montaza Palace grounds first had the Salamlek Palace, built in 1892 by Khedive Abbas II, the last Muhammad Ali Dynasty ruler to hold the Khedive title over the Khedivate of Egypt and Sudan. It was used as a hunting lodge and residence for his companion .The larger Al-Haramlik Palace and royal gardens were added to the Montaza Palace grounds, being built by King Fuad I in 1932, as a summer palace. It is in a mixture of Ottoman and Florentine styles, with two towers. One of these towers rises distinctively high above with elaborated Italian Renaissance design details. The palace has long open arcades facing the sea along each floor. President Anwar El-Sadat renovated the original Salamlek Palace as an official presidential residence. It was most recently used by former president Hosni Mubarak.</string>
    <string name="greco_roman">The Graeco-Roman Museum is an archaeological museum located in Alexandria, Egypt. Erected in 1892, it was first built in a five-room apartment, inside one small building on Rosetta Street (later Avenue Canope and now Horriya). In 1895, it was transferred to another, larger building near Gamal Abdul Nasser Street. The museum contains several pieces dating from the Greco-Roman (Ptolemaic) era in the 3rd century BC, such as a sculpture of Apis in black granite, the sacred bull of the Egyptians, mummies, sarcophagus, tapestries, and other objects offering a view of Greco-Roman civilization in contact with ancient Egypt.</string>
    <string name="roman_amphitheatre">The Roman Amphitheatre we see today in Alexandria was constructed in the 4th century AD and it was a common feature of the Greco Roman period. Amphitheaters were special roofed theatres that were built to host music ceremonies and poet competitions during the reign of the Romans in Egypt.The amphitheatre features a marble audience section which is symmetrical with extended wing and could host up 600 spectators. The audience section has a diameter of about 33 meters and consists of 13 rows made of European white marble with the uppermost part being a portico made out of granite columns that were brought from Aswan and some of them are still standing until today. The thirteen rows of the Roman Amphitheatre of Alexandria were numbered with Roman digits and letters to regulate the seating of the audience on different occasions.</string>
    <string name="saint_marc">is an all-male French Roman Catholic school in Alexandria, Egypt. The school is located in the Shatby neighborhood at downtown Alexandria.Collège Saint Marc was founded in 1928 by the De La Salle Brothers to be the second Lassalian school in Alexandria after Ecole Sainte Catherine. Collège Saint Marc was inaugurated on 6 October 1928, by King Fuad I. Built on an area of 35,726 m2, it was at the time of its inauguration the largest educational institution in the Middle East.Collège Saint Marc is a private educational institution with French as its main teaching language. Students must be accepted beginning at KG1, and successful students remain in the school until they receive their high school diploma. The curriculum at Collège Saint Marc prepares the students for the Egyptian Baccalaureate examination</string>
    <string name="unknown_soldier">The Alexandria Naval Unknown Soldier Memorial at the Manshaya district is dedicated to the unknown soldiers who lost their lives in the sea battles, it is present on the Corniche of Alexandria. It was built under the rule of Muhammed Ali of Egypt as Alexandria was the main naval base for his son Ibrahim Pashas expedition to Greece during the Greek War of Independence, that culminated in the Battle of Navarino.</string>
    <string name="bibliotheca">is a major library and cultural center located on the shore of the Mediterranean Sea in the Egyptian city of Alexandria. It is both a commemoration of the Library of Alexandria that was lost in antiquity, and an attempt to rekindle something of the brilliance that this earlier center of study and erudition represented. The idea of reviving the old library dates back to 1974, when a committee set up by Alexandria University selected a plot of land for its new library. Construction work began in 1995 and, after some US $220 million had been spent, the complex was officially inaugurated on 16 October 2002. In 2010, the library received a donation of 500,000 books from the Bibliothèque nationale de France (BnF). The gift makes the Bibliotheca Alexandrina the sixth-largest Francophone library in the world.</string>
    <string name="saad_zhagloul">was an Egyptian revolutionary and statesman. He was the leader of Egypt\'s nationalist Wafd Party. He served as Prime Minister of Egypt from 26 January 1924 to 24 November 1924.</string>
    <string name="qaitbay">is a 15th-century defensive fortress located on the Mediterranean sea coast, in Alexandria, Egypt. It was established in 1477 AD  by Sultan Al-Ashraf Sayf al-Din Qait Bay. The Citadel is situated on the eastern side of the northern tip of Pharos Island at the mouth of the Eastern Harbour.</string>
</resources>
